<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Golang on CyrillSchumacher.com</title>
        <link>http://cyrillschumacher.com/tags/golang/</link>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <author>Cyrill at Schumacher dot fm</author>
        <rights>Copyright (c) 2014, Cyrill Schumacher; all rights reserved.</rights>
        <updated>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
        
        <item>
            <title>How to speed up the GoLang based Onix parser?</title>
            <link>http://cyrillschumacher.com/2014/12/14/how-to-speed-up-the-golang-based-onix-parser/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
            <author>Cyrill at Schumacher dot fm</author>
            <guid>http://cyrillschumacher.com/2014/12/14/how-to-speed-up-the-golang-based-onix-parser/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Bacon ipsum dolor amet short ribs t-bone drumstick chicken, kielbasa ball tip porchetta sirloin kevin corned beef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turducken pork chop rump, spare ribs pork belly salami ribeye shoulder shankle pork loin tail bresaola short loin. Ball tip chuck t-bone prosciutto beef ground round ribeye cupim pork chop short ribs bresaola. Filet mignon ball tip jerky pork loin tenderloin hamburger t-bone chicken andouille cupim brisket sausage spare ribs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ham hock picanha venison tail drumstick, short ribs pork loin beef kevin pork fatback doner. Filet mignon beef flank, cupim alcatra jerky short loin turducken hamburger porchetta tri-tip. Ground round chicken pastrami filet mignon landjaeger jerky, tri-tip tail beef. Cupim spare ribs tail alcatra chuck bacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerky ribeye ham salami beef landjaeger biltong. Flank pancetta pork loin salami. Cupim kevin pig, biltong capicola porchetta pastrami pork spare ribs pork belly corned beef chicken drumstick turkey hamburger. Ball tip pork belly bresaola hamburger t-bone short loin pastrami boudin jerky drumstick alcatra. Short loin ham hock andouille jerky, pork belly pastrami pig chicken venison shoulder. Kevin pig turducken, strip steak doner tongue spare ribs venison pancetta sirloin ham hock. Jowl chuck cow, pork ham shoulder bacon pig pork loin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capicola sirloin jowl ribeye t-bone chicken turducken pastrami landjaeger pork belly filet mignon flank tri-tip. T-bone pancetta tenderloin venison. Tongue andouille hamburger, bacon pork shoulder tri-tip strip steak prosciutto alcatra pork belly picanha kevin. Leberkas tenderloin cow porchetta jowl turkey turducken bacon. Frankfurter boudin ham hock, pancetta kevin landjaeger prosciutto ground round strip steak fatback. Pancetta flank capicola, beef ribs sausage tail meatloaf leberkas ham hock filet mignon drumstick kielbasa rump. Biltong kevin tenderloin ham hock, t-bone meatball salami tongue frankfurter ham ribeye cow pork chop shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porchetta beef ribs pork drumstick ribeye tongue. Pork loin rump pastrami bacon brisket capicola salami ball tip picanha. Hamburger ball tip spare ribs prosciutto meatball chuck. Ball tip porchetta ham hock turkey tri-tip, spare ribs rump kielbasa. Meatloaf brisket doner short loin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>OnixParser</title>
            <link>http://cyrillschumacher.com/projects/2014-06-29-onixparser-golang/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
            <author>Cyrill at Schumacher dot fm</author>
            <guid>http://cyrillschumacher.com/projects/2014-06-29-onixparser-golang/</guid>
            <description>

&lt;p&gt;Onix Parser written in GoLang to deal with huge XML file sizes. The ONIX for Books Product Information
Message is the international standard for representing and communicating book industry product
information in electronic form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Latest commit and statistics from GitHub:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;hubinfo&#34; data-u=&#34;SchumacherFM&#34; data-r=&#34;OnixParser&#34; data-c=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A parser for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.editeur.org/83/Overview/&#34;&gt;EDItEUR ONIX xml file format&lt;/a&gt; written in GoLang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first learning project. Of course it contains many &lt;em&gt;mistakes&lt;/em&gt; but the binary runs quite nice and at Zookal.com we&amp;rsquo;re
using it in production. If you find an error or incorrect usage of Go, let me know :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired for learning by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.davidsingleton.org/parsing-huge-xml-files-with-go/&#34;&gt;http://blog.davidsingleton.org/parsing-huge-xml-files-with-go/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;xml-data:a44564a0a74e2cbf21533d898d45bce4&#34;&gt;XML Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.editeur.org/onix/2.1/02/reference/onix-international.dtd&#34;&gt;http://www.editeur.org/onix/2.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;02&lt;/sub&gt;/reference/onix-international.dtd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;test-data-onix-data-feed:a44564a0a74e2cbf21533d898d45bce4&#34;&gt;Test data Onix Data Feed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download test data from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oup.com.au/help_and_advice/booksellers&#34;&gt;http://www.oup.com.au/help_and_advice/booksellers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Complete File or The Incremental File.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all XML elements are matched because structure in DTD is unclear and we don&amp;rsquo;t need all elements. If one element is
missing send me an email or a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance:a44564a0a74e2cbf21533d898d45bce4&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parsing a &lt;strong&gt;3GB XML&lt;/strong&gt; file with &lt;strong&gt;998673 products&lt;/strong&gt; needs &lt;strong&gt;14m36.525541544s&lt;/strong&gt; to import that data &lt;strong&gt;into MySQL 5.5&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;13-inch, Mid 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processor  1.8 GHz Intel Core i5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory  8 GB 1600 MHz DDR3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APPLE SATA SSD SM256E Media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several options on the command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ go run OnixParser.go -h
OnixParser Copyright (C) 2014 Cyrill AT Schumacher dot fm
This program comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY; License: http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html
Usage of OnixParser:
  -db=&amp;quot;test&amp;quot;: MySQL db name
  -host=&amp;quot;127.0.0.1&amp;quot;: MySQL host name
  -infile=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;: Input file path
  -logfile=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;: Logfile name, if empty direct output
  -moc=20: Max MySQL open connections
  -outdir=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;: Dir for CSV output file for reading into MySQL, if empty writes to /tmp/
  -pass=&amp;quot;test&amp;quot;: MySQL password
  -tablePrefix=&amp;quot;gonix_&amp;quot;: Table name prefix
  -user=&amp;quot;test&amp;quot;: MySQL user name
  -v=false: Increase verbosity
exit status 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed of import can only be achieved by using &lt;code&gt;LOAD DATA INFILE LOCAL&lt;/code&gt; with MySQL. So check your config if the option
has been enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;installation:a44564a0a74e2cbf21533d898d45bce4&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install the command line program, use the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Go: &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/doc/install&#34;&gt;http://golang.org/doc/install&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;go get github.com/SchumacherFM/OnixParser
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;license:a44564a0a74e2cbf21533d898d45bce4&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Public License&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
